Register of the Sidney Hook papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Lecture Notes, undated (Boxes 102-109)
  - Logic in Action [lecture series] (Folder 16)
    - 8. Scientific Method contra Dialectics (Folder 24)
    - 9. How Liars "Figger" (Folder 25)
    - 10. Argumenta Ad Hominem: Open and Hidden (Folder 26)
    - 11. Logic and Myth in Politics (Folder 27)
    - 12. The Logic of Means and Ends (Folder 28)
    - 13. Scientific Cause and Logical Ground (Folder 29)
    - 14. Propaganda in Propaganda Analysis (Folder 30)
    - 15. Philosophical Interpretations in Logic (Folder 31)
  - The Logic of Hypotheses (Folder 32)
  - Logical Positivism (Folder 33)
  - Lukacs (Georg) (Folder 34)
  - Machiavelli to Mussolini (Folder 35)
  - Marx (Karl) (Folder 36)
  - Marx and Engels (Folder 37)
  - Marx and Socialist Society (Folder 38)
  - Marx and the Present (Folder 39)
  - Marx and the Young Hegelians (Folder 40)
  - Marx as a Philosopher (Folder 41)
  - Marx's Challenge to the West (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Marx's Economics: Costs of Revolution (Folder 2)
  - Marx's Theory of Classes (Folder 3)
  - Marx's Theory of Ideology (Folder 4)
  - Marxism and Communism (Folder 5)
  - Marxism and Leninism (Folder 6)
  - Marxism and Modern Philosophy (Folder 7)
  - Marxism and Modern Science (Folder 8)
  - Marxism Today (Folder 9)
  - Material Achievement and Spiritual Development (Folder 10)
  - Materialism (Folder 11)
  - The Materialist Conception of History (Folder 12)
  - Meaning and Verification (Folder 13)
  - The Meaning of History (Folder 14)
  - The Meaning of Present-Day Liberalism (Folder 15)
  - Mechanism (Folder 16)
  - Mechanism and Vitalism (Folder 17)
  - The Melting Pot? (Folder 18)
  - Metaphysics (Folder 19)
  - Metaphysics as Nonsense (Folder 20)
  - The Methodology of Marx (Folder 21)
  - The Mind of the Twentieth Century (Folder 22)
  - Modern Anthropological Thought (Folder 23)
  - Myth and Reality in the Struggle for the World (Folder 24)
  - Nationalism as an Expression of Early Democracy (Folder 25)
  - Natural Law (Folder 26)
  - Naturalism (Folder 27)
  - Nature and Role of Revolutionary Ideals (Folder 28)
  - The Nature of Chance (Folder 29)
  - The Nature of Ideas in History (Folder 30)
  - Necessary Being (Folder 31)
  - Neo-Thomism (Folder 32)
  - The New Conservatism and the Old Liberalism (Folder 33)
  - New Criticism (Folder 34)
  - New Directions in Socialist Thought (Folder 35)
  - Year of Decision?, 1944: (Folder 36)
  - Our Rights and Obligations Under the Constitution (Folder 37)
  - Pareto (Vilfredo) (Folder 38)
  - Pareto, Mosca and Michels (Folder 39)
  - Peace and the Future of Jewry (Folder 40)
  - The Philosophical Basis of American Socialism (Folder 41)
  - Philosophy (Folder 42)
  - Philosophy and Our Daily Bread (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy and the Modern World (Folder 2)
  - The Philosophy of Capitalism (Folder 3)
  - Philosophy of Cultural Freedom (Folder 4)
  - The Philosophy of Dialectical Materialism (Folder 5)
  - Philosophy of History [general] (Folder 6)
  - Philosophy of History [lecture series] (Folder 7)
    - General
    - 1. Philosophy of Civilization (Folder 8)
    - 2. The Theory of Social Evolution (Folder 9)
    - 3. Critique of Evolution (Folder 10)
    - 4. Diffusionism and the Historico-Genetic Method (Folder 11)
    - 5. Geographical Interpretations of Civilization (Folder 12)
    - 6. The Racial Interpretation of Civilization (Folder 13)
    - 7. Genetics, Eugenics and Selectionism (Folder 14)
    - 8. The Use and Abuse of Statistical Method in Social Theory (Folder 15)
    - 9. The Heroic Conception of History and Civilization (Folder 16)
    - 10. Theories of Group-Consciousness (Folder 17)
    - 11. The Biological Interpretation of Civilization (Folder 18)
    - 12. Psychological Interpretations of Civilization (Folder 19)
    - 13. Durkheim and the Sociological Interpretation of the Categories (Folder 20)
    - 14. The Materialistic Conception of History (Folder 21)
    - 15. The Nature of History (Folder 22)
    - 16. Law and Chance in Human History (Folder 23)
  - Philosophy of Jewish History (Folder 24)
  - Philosophy of John Dewey (Folder 25)
  - The Philosophy of Thomas Jefferson (Folder 26)
  - Place of Philosophy in the American Tradition (Folder 27)
  - The Place of the Humanities in a Liberal Arts Education (Folder 28)
  - Plato's Republic (Folder 29)
  - The Politics of the Academy (Folder 30)
  - Potentiality (Folder 31)
  - Pragmatism as a Philosophy of Experimentalism (Folder 32)
  - Present and Future of Marxism (Folder 33)
  - The President's Committee on Civil Rights (Folder 34)
  - Problems and Prospects of World History (Folder 35)
  - Problems in Social and Political Philosophy (Folder 36)
  - The Professor, Academic Freedom and Responsibility (Folder 37)
  - A Progressive Educator Talks Back (Folder 38)
  - Property (Folder 39)
  - The Prospects of Jewish Group Survival in America (Folder 40)
  - Qualities of Political Leadership (Folder 41)
  - Rationalism (Folder 42)
  - Realistic Democracy (Folder 43)
  - Reason, Fact and Fetish in History (Folder 44)
  - Reflections on Detente (Folder 45)
  - Relevance of Philosophy in an Experimental Age (Folder 46)
  - Religion (Folder 47)
  - Religion and the Social Order (Folder 48)
  - The Revival of Metaphysics (Folder 49)
  - The Rights and Limits of Dissent (Folder 50)
  - Rights of Students (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - The Rise of the Masses to Self-Consciousness (Folder 2)
  - Rousseau (Jean-Jacques) (Folder 3)
  - Russell (Bertrand) (Folder 4)
  - Russia (Folder 5)
  - Russia's Psychological Pressures (Folder 6)
  - Santayana and the Life of Reason (Folder 7)
  - Sartre and Existentialism (Folder 8)
  - Scheler (Max) (Folder 9)
  - Science and Humanities (Folder 10)
  - Scope of Marxian Theory (Folder 11)
  - A Secular Scheme of Personal Values (Folder 12)
  - Skepticism and Certainty (Folder 13)
  - A Social Philosophy for Jews (Folder 14)
  - Social Thought in America (Folder 15)
  - Socialism and Freedom (Folder 16)
  - Socialism: Utopian and Scientific (Folder 17)
  - Sorel (Georges) (Folder 18)
  - Sources of Jewish Culture (Folder 19)
  - Soviet Foreign Policy (Folder 20)
  - Space (Folder 21)
  - Spengler Reconsidered (Folder 22)
  - Spengler's Political and Social Philosophy (Folder 23)
  - Spinoza (Benedict) (Folder 24)
  - Substance (Folder 25)
  - Suicide (Folder 26)
  - Teaching Adults (Folder 27)
  - Teaching of Communism in the Colleges (Folder 28)
  - Temporal Propositions: Judgments of the Past (Folder 29)
  - The Theory of Plural Priorities (Folder 30)
  - Theory of Universals (Folder 31)
  - Thinking (Folder 32)
  - Three Generic Conceptions of Experience (Folder 33)
  - Tillich (Paul) (Folder 34)
  - Time (Folder 35)
  - Today's Flight from Reason (Folder 36)
  - Totalitarianism and the American Tradition (Folder 37)
  - Toynbee (Arnold J.) (Folder 38)
  - Truth (Folder 39)
  - Values and Public Social Policy (Folder 40)
  - Values in a Changing Society (Folder 41)
  - Voltaire (Folder 42)
  - Wallace (Henry A.) (Folder 43)
  - Weber (Max) (Folder 44)
  - What Is Living and Dead in Marxism? (Folder 45)
  - What Is Philosophy? (Folder 46)
  - What Is the Outlook for American Democracy? (Folder 47)
  - What Is Truth? (Folder 48)
  - What Is Workers' Democracy? (Folder 49)
  - Whitehead (Alfred North) (Folder 50)
  - Why Capital Is an Important Book (Folder 51)
  - Why Europe and America Must Unite (Folder 52)
  - Why Hegel Is Important (Folder 53)
  - The World We Live In (Folder 54)
- Subject File, 1904-1990 (Boxes 110-172)
  Published and unpublished writings of others, correspondence, and other material, arranged alphabetically by the topic to which they relate. See also: Addendum File.
  - General. Correspondence, clippings, notes, press release, flyers, printed articles, and miscellany, 1932-1988 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Abortion. Printed article and letter, 1985-1989 (Folder 2)
  - Abzug, Bella. Clippings, flyers, and letters by Gerald Pinsky, 1972-1986 (Folder 3)
  - Academy of Humanism. Statement of purpose, by-laws, and letters by Cynthia Ozick, Paul Kurtz and Carl Sagan, 1983 (Folder 4)
  - Academy of Independent Scholars (Proposed). Prospectus, and correspondence with Kenneth E. Boulding and Lawrence Senesh, 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Adler, Mortimer J. Mimeographed lectures and printed articles by Adler, notes, clippings, and correspondence with Philip Burnham, Louis Finkelstein, Martin Gardner, Henry Hurwitz, Henry R. Luce, T. S. Matthews, Arthur S. Murphy and others, 1936-1957 (Folder 6)
  - Afghanistan. Newsletter, letter, speech by Jeane Kirkpatrick, and clipping, 1981-1983. (Folder 7)
  - Africa. Speech by Jeane Kirkpatrick, mimeographed copy of S. L. A. Marshall, "South Africa: The Strategic View," letters, clippings, and leaflet, 1959-1989 (Folder 8)
  - Alienation. Notes, printed copies of articles, typescript copies of Edmund Demaitre, "Modernists vs. Manicheans: The Marxist Debate on Socialist Humanism," Lewis S. Feuer, "Western Marxism: Its Search for a Philosophy," and Paul Craig Roberts and Matthew A. Stephenson, "The Concept of Alienation in Marx's Capital," and letters by Jeff M. Elliot and Dan Levin, 1961-1971 (Folder 9)
  - Amerasia. Printed copy of Philip J. Jaffe, The Amerasia Case from 1945 to Present (pamphlet), typescript copy of Harvey Klehr and Ronald Radosh, "The Amerasia Case and McCarthyism," and corerspondence with Klehr, 1979-1988 (Folder 10)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Application forms, bulletins, and correspondence with the Academy, George Shuster, John Voss and another, 1960-1985 (Folder 11)
  - American Artists' Congress. Printed copies of First American Artists Congress, 1936 and Art Front, and correspondence and printed article by Gerald Monroe, 1936-1976 (Folder 12)
  - American Association of Scientific Workers. Letters by Mark Graubard, 1940 (Folder 13)
  - American Civil Liberties Union. Printed copy of Crisis in the Civil Liberties Union (pamphlet), printed interview with Roger Baldwin, resolutions and ephemeral publications of the American Civil Liberties Union, clippings, printed articles, and correspondence with Baldwin, Robert Berkman, John L. Childs and others, 1939-1989 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom. Printed and mimeographed issuances of the American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom, clippings, press releases issued by Harry D. Gideonse, and correspondence with Franz Boas, Ralph E. Himstead and Harlow Shapley, 1939-1941 (Folder 2)
  - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky. Printed copy of Leon Trotsky, I Stake My Life (pamphlet), and correspondence with Thurman Arnold, Newton Arvin, Morris R. Cohen, Jerome Davis, Sherwood Eddy, Felix Frankfurter, Horace M. Kallen, Robert Morss Lovett, Arthur O. Lovejoy, Upton Sinclair, T. V. Smith, Stephen S. Wise and others, 1937 (Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations. Printed and mimeographed issuances of the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1962-1979 (Folder 4)
  - American Humanist Association. Legal briefs, printed and non-printed issuances of the American Humanist Association, and correspondence with John Dewey, Horace M. Kallen, Paul Kurtz, Edwin H. Wilson and others, 1942-1979 (Folder 5-6)
  - American Labor Party. Leaflet, and correspondence with William Ernest Hocking, Kenneth Leslie, Reinhold Niebuhr and others, 1940-1943 (Folder 7)
  - American Philosophical Association. Issuances and proposed resolutions of the American Philosophical Association, programs, clippings, and correspondence with Brand Blanshard, Nicholas Capaldi, John J. Compton, Harold J. Johnson, Cornelius Kruse, Maurice Mandelbaum, Milton C. Nahm, Alan Pasch, Philip Blair Rice and others, 1930-1988 (Box 112, Folder 1-2)
  - American Workers Party. Correspondence with Hubert Bonner, James Burnham, Robert M. Lovett, Herbert Solow, Allen Stiller, Arthur Younger and others, printed issuances, newsletter, clippings, and notes, 1934-1979 (Folder 3)
  - American Writers' Congress. Printed article by John Chamberlain, "The Literary Left Grows Up,", 1935 (Folder 4)
  - Americans for Intellectual Freedom. Includes material relating to the Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace
    - Correspondence with A. J. Ayer, Rudolf Carnap, George Counts, Irwin Edman, Albert Einstein, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, William Ernest Hocking, Robert Morss Lovett, Henry R. Luce, Robert S. Lynd, Thomas Mann, H. J. Muller, Curtis P. Nettels, Harlow Shapley, Guy Emery Shipler, Rexford G. Tugwell, Oswald Veblen and others, 1949-1983 (Folder 5)
    - Miscellany. Press releases, program, clippings, printed matter, reports, and mimeographed copy of George S. Counts, "The Soviet Ideological Assault on the West,", 1949-1989 (Folder 6)
  - Anarchism. Outline, clipping, report, and correspondence, 1969-1985 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Arendt, Hannah. Printed copy of On Revolution, with notes by Hook, printed articles, and correspondence with Lewis Feuer, Melvin Lasky, Diana Trilling and others, 1953-1986 (Folder 2)
  - Argentina. Memorandum, clippings, and correspondence with Brand Blanshard, Ernesto Bonasso, Edgar S. Brightman, Marvin Farber, Risieri Frondizi, Cornelius Kruse, Hans Reichenbach, Paul Weiss and others, 1948-1950 (Folder 3)
  - Art and esthetics. Printed matter, and correspondence with Meyer Schapiro, Morris Weitz and others, 1941-1969 (Folder 4)
  - Atheism. Notes, atheist propaganda issuances, and correspondence, 1930-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Atomic weapons and disarmament
    - Correspondence with Herman Kahn, Edwin Meese III, Roger O'Toole, Edward J. Rozek, Elias M. Schwarzbart, DeWitt S. Snell, Edward Teller, Dorothy Thompson and others, 1946-1986 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellany. Notes, announcements, newsletters, report, mimeograph outline, anonymous untitled mimeographed study, untitled mimeographed speeches by David Emery and Henry Kissinger, untitled mimeographed statements by the AFL-CIO and Eugene V. Rostow, mimeographed copy of Donald G. Brennan, "SALT and Arms Control," and typescript copy of Cuthbert Daniel and Arthur M. Squires, "The First Step to World Disarmament,", 1948-1986 (Folder 7)
    - Printed matter. Leaflets, bulletins, clippings, periodical issues, pamphlets, printed articles by Edward Teller and others, and reprints
      - 1947-1981 (Folder 8-9)
      - 1982-1986 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Australia. Periodical issues, and letters, 1968-1978 (Folder 2)
  - Authoritarianism. Untitled typescript speech by Arnold Dresden, printed articles, and letter from Seymour Lipset, 1981-1989 (Folder 3)
  - Beard, Charles A. Letters, 1975-1978 (Folder 4)
  - Bell, Daniel. Typescript copies of two studies by Daniel Bell, "Technology, Nature and Society: The Vicissitudes of Three World-Views and the Confusion of Realms" and "The Basic Structures of Knowledge: What We May No Longer Take for Granted," and letters, 1969-1983 (Folder 5)
  - Bentley, Arthur F. Printed biographical sketch, 1968 (Folder 6)
  - Bergson, Henri. Typescript copy of Richard Gale, "Bergson's Analysis of the Concept of Nothing," and correspondence, 1964-1965 (Folder 7)
  - Berlin. Freie Universitdt. Correspondence with J|rgen Domes, Werner Stein, and Otto Stoltz, 1948-1973 (Folder 8)
  - Berlin, Isaiah. Printed articles and letter, 1963-1982 (Folder 9)
  - Bernstein, Eduard. Printed article and notes, 1978 (Folder 10)
  - Bloom, Allan. Printed articles, typescript copies of Kenneth Eble, "The Degradation of Undergraduate Education," and Jean Bethke Elshtain, "Relying on Nature: Are You Eligible for Membership in Allan Bloom's Fraternity?" Joseph Epstein, "Great Books, Democracy and Truth," Floyd W. Hayes III, "The Politics of Education in America's Multicultural Society: Beyond Bloom's Lament," Kathleen B. Jones, "Discourse, Text and Gender: A Women's Studies Response to The Closing of the American Mind," Stephen B. W. Roeder, "Can Science and Reason Have Anything to Say About Our Values? A Naive View," and Kingsley Widmer, "An Apology for Unteaching," and letters by Ted Klein and others, 1987-1989 (Folder 11)
  - Boas, Franz. Correspondence with Michael Rosen, 1983 (Folder 12)
  - Boas, George. Printed article and letter, 1984 (Folder 13)
  - Bogdanov, Alexander. Letters, newsletters and printed articles by K. M. Jensen, 1982 (Folder 14)
  - Brecht, Bertolt. Notes, program, printed article, clippings, reprints, and correspondence with Hans-J|rgen Caspar, 1957-1988 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Bukharin, Nikolai. Printed matter, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Bunzel, John H. Clippings, reprint, mimeographed and printed copies of speeches by John H. Bunzel, and correspondence with Glenn Dumke, Paul Seabury, Philip Siegelman, and others, 1968-1983 (Folder 3)
  - Burma. Pamphlets and letter, 1954-1959 (Folder 4)
  - Burnham, James. Correspondence with Lewis Feuer and another, 1981-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Burtt, Edwin A. Booklet and notes, 1988 (Folder 6)
  - Calverton, V. F. Printed article and correspondence, 1933-1988 (Folder 7)
  - Cambodia. Speech by Jeane Kirkpatrick, 1984 (Folder 8)
  - Catholic Church. Legal document, clippings, other printed matter, and correspondence with J. P. Conneally, Ferdinand Lundberg and others, 1939-1985 (Folder 9)
  - Catholic/Humanist Dialogue, Typescript copy of opening remarks by Paul Kurtz, and mimeographed copies of two conference papers, Charles Frankel, "Conscience and the State," and J. P. Mackey, "The Sources and Sanctions of Conscience," 1972 (Folder 10)
  - Censorship. Clippings, correspondence, and legal brief, 1947-1987 (Folder 11)
  - Central America. Symposium paper by Melvin Levitsky, clippings, position papers, typescript reports by Max Singer, statements by Singer and Jeane Kirkpatrick, printed articles, and correspondence with James Jefford, R. Bruce McColm, Stephen Solarz and others, Primarily relates to Nicaragua and El Salvador, 1981-1989. (Folder 12)
  - Chemical warfare. Statement by Stephen J. Solarz, 1983 (Folder 13)
  - Chile. Legal decision, and printed matter, 1979 (Folder 14)
  - China. Correspondence and printed article by Miriam London, 1983-1985 (Folder 15)
  - Chomsky, Noam. Printed articles by Chomsky and others, pamphlet, copies of Chomsky speech in Hanoi, and correspondence with Chomsky, Milton R. Konvitz, George Watson, Arthur M. Young and others, 1968-1989 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Cities and towns. Pamphlet, 1966 (Folder 2)
  - Civil disobedience. Notes, reports, untitled mimeographed essay by Michael Walzer, typescript copies of Alan Gewirth, "Civil Disobedience, Law and Morality: An Examination of Justice Fortas' Doctrine," and Robert H. Sulnick, "The Conscientious Objector: A Matter of Justice and Freedom of Religion," letters, speeches, printed article, clipping, and bulletin, ca. 1960-1976 (Folder 3)
  - Civil rights
    - Miscellany. Notes, mimeographed material, mimeographed copies of W. T. Blackstone, "Equality and Human Rights," Herbert Brucker, "Freedom vs. Treason," Harry V. Jaffa, "The American Founding as the Best Regime: The Bonding of Civil and Religious Liberty," and Roger Pilon, "A Theory of Rights," and correspondence with Birch Bayh, Norman Dorsen and others, 1948-1987 (Folder 4)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, articles, serial issues, pamphlets, letters, and leaflets, 1909-1987 (Folder 5-6)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge. Untitled typescript article by Eldridge Cleaver, and letter by Carl Gershman (Folder 7)
  - Cohen, Morris R.
    - Lectures. Handwritten and typewritten transcripts of lectures by Morris R. Cohen (Box 117, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellany. Lecture notices, program, printed articles by Cohen, and correspondence with Felix S. Cohen, Leonora Cohen Rosenfield, and others, 1923-1971 (Folder 3)
  - Colorado, University of. Printed material, memoranda, galley proofs, speeches, and correspondence with Edward Rozek and others, 1957-1988 (Folder 4)
  - Commager, Henry Steele. Printed articles by Commager, and letters by Arnold Beichman and another, 1949-1987 (Folder 5)
  - Commission pour la Viriti sur les Crimes de Staline. Memorandum, 1961 (Folder 6)
  - Committee for Cultural Freedom. Includes material relating to the League for Cultural Freedom and Socialism
    - Correspondence with Sherwood Anderson, Roger Baldwin, Franz Boas, Walter B. Cannon, Felix S. Cohen, Philip W. L. Cox, John Dewey, Irving Fineman, Waldo Frank, Francis A. Henson, Ralph Ingersoll, Freda Kirchwey, Suzanne La Follette, Max Lerner, Arthur Lovejoy, Ferdinand Lundberg, Wesley C. Mitchell, John Jacob Posner, Benjamin Stolberg, Norman Thomas, Harry F. Ward and others, 1939-1988 (Folder 7)
    - Miscellany. Printed and mimeographed issuances, program statements, minutes, reports, clippings, press releases, bulletins, lists, and miscellany, 1939-1942 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Committee for the Free World. Press releases, clippings, membership list, typescript copy of Melvin J. Lasky, "On Ideas, Ideology, and Information Policy in the 1980's," and correspondence with John S. Friedman, Leopold Labedz, Cleo Mitchell Paturis, Leo Raditsa, and Philip Siegelman, 1981-1983 (Folder 2)
  - Committee on Science and Freedom (sponsored by the Congress for Cultural Freedom). Correspondence with George, Michael and Priscilla Polanyi, 1954-1965 (Folder 3)
  - Common Cause. Printed matter, and correspondence, 1949 (Folder 4)
  - Communism
    - General. Clippings, reprints, serial issues, other printed matter, mimeographed material, notes, memorandum by Seymour Martin Lipset, and correspondence, 1932-1984 (Folder 5-6)
    - China. Clippings, printed material, mimeograph and printed issuances of the American China Policy Association, Inc., speeches by Clare Boothe Luce, A. C. Wedemeyer, and others, pamphlet, typescript copy of Mary F. Berry, "The Chinese Experience in Education: What America Stands to Learn," mimeograph copy of "Wang Tsun-ming, Anti-Communist: An Autobiographical Account of Chinese Communist Thought Reform," typescript copy of a letter to the editor by Abraham Kalish relating to John Paton Davies, and correspondence with Alfred Kohlberg, Lynn H. Miller, and Albert Shanker, 1934-1983 (Folder 7)
    - Cuba. Mimeographed statement by Carl Gershman, clippings, other printed matter, and letters by Theodore Draper and others, 1962-1985 (Folder 8)
    - Czechoslovakia. Clippings, mimeographed and typescript material, serial issue, typescript copy of "Cultural Detente at Scientific Congresses: The Secret Report of the Czech Sociologists to the Central Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party, 1974," and letters, 1946-1986 (Folder 9)
    - Europe, Eastern. Reprint, conference proceedings, bulletin relating to Hungary, printed material, and mimeographed copy of Brutus Coste, "Our Allies Behind the Iron Curtain,", 1950-1957 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Korea. Anonymous untitled typescript study, n.d. (Folder 2)
    - Poland. Typescript copy of Leszek Kolakowski, "The Phenomenon of Polish Marxism," mimeographed proceedings of the East-West Round Table of New York, clippings, press release, pamphlet, and correspondence with Kolakowski and Saul E. White, 1946-1982 (Folder 3)
    - Soviet Union
      - Clippings, 1929-1983 (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence with Curtis Benjamin, Albert Einstein, Jerzy Gliksman, Alice G. Harris, Thomas Mann, Philip F. Mayer, Donald C. Williams and others, 1947-1988 (Folder 5)
      - Miscellany. Printed articles, clippings, notes, pamphlets, serial issues, printed and mimeographed bulletins, press release, and a mimeographed copy of Roman Smal-Stocky, "The American Committee for Free Russia and the Right of Self-Determination of the Non-Russian Nationalities of the Soviet Union,", 1921-1984 (Folder 6-7)
    - United States
      - Clippings, 1935-1988 (Folder 8)